#### **Contact**

0815445681

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahishramkisson-678552116/

# AHISH RAMKISSOON

Software Developer | | Network Engineer

#### Personal details

Date of birth: 13/10/1994

Nationality: South African

Languages: Proficient in English, Basic Afrikaans and Zulu

囩

Driver's license: Code 08

### **SUMMARY**

Network engineer with over 5 years of experience in communication networks. I am graduating tertiary education with a Higher Certificate in Information Systems (Engineering). My passion lies in programming and striving to obtain the experience necessary to become a full-stack developer. So, my learning and education will continue.

I am a dedicated professional in the IT field with focus in improving quality and efficiency. I am committed to providing high quality work ethic with an enthusiastic ability to continuously learn and adapt to new technologies.

## Certificates and licenses



#### CompTIA N++

(March 2020 - April 2023) COMP001021650621



## Huawei HCIA Routing & Switching

(October 2020 – October 2023)

### **EXPERIENCE**

<sup>A≡</sup> Senior Support Engineer | PSI It Services

May 2023 - Present

# RESENIOR NETWORK ENGINEER | IN2IT TECHNOLOGIES PTY

#### February 2018 - Present

Project – LIQUID TELECOM

#### Responsibilities:

- Working with Remedy, ServiceNow, Cramer (web report),
   DaloRADIUS Ticketing tool, handle Transnet networks and
   Liquid Telecoms devices.
- Trouble shoot connectivity, customer care.
- Maintain and receive quotes for hardware infrastructure products

#### **Achievements**



## Outstanding Customer Service 2018

**IN2IT TECHNOLOGIES PTY LTD** 

#### **Education**



Higher Certificate in Information Systems Engineering Eduvos

2021 - 2023

(Elective Programming major: C#)



Diploma in Office
Administration
Quest Computer Skills Center
2016



**Dynamix Learning Solutions** 2014



**%** 

**Rand Tutorial College** 

2013



Matric 2012

# RE TEAM LEAD AND SERVICE DESK ADMINISTRATOR | IN2IT

#### November 2016 - January 2018

Project - SILICA

#### Responsibilities:

- Administered and prepared programs for IP addresses
- Developed network resources and trained support personnel to provide Tier I support to end users
- Managed a Team of 15 people to ensure daily operation of the project
- Monitored servers and escalated emergency technical issues beyond scope to maintain optimum up-time
- Provided complete end-to-end engineering and installation of route-based IP network solutions
- Demonstrated strong analytical, troubleshooting and problem-solving skills
- Contributed to implementation and support of SNMP monitoring software, application manager and other network monitoring tools
- Tool support for manage engine tool set
- Service desk support -hands on experience in working with tickets, complete lifecycle
- Preparing daily, weekly and monthly reports for customers
- Management of servers, switches, IP phones grand stream,
   PC, Laptop, software upgrades.
- Asset management

### AE ADMINISTRATION CLERK | MAC EASY IT

#### April 2015 - July 2016

#### Responsibilities:

- Knowledgeable and qualified in office administration
- Compiling work packs
- Managing reception
- Administrating director's appointments
- Banking of funds
- Facilitating record keeping
- Assisting in sales and repairs
- Issuing of Invoices

# A Administration clerk and travel consultant | RC

#### October 2014 - March 2015

#### Responsibilities:

- Position Administration clerk/ travel consultant
- Knowledgeable and experienced in office administration
- Confirming and booking of travel for clients
- Preparing daily accounting spreadsheets
- Assisting in customer support and gueries

#### **Personal Skills**

- RR Interpersonal and management communication skills
- R Problem solving and critical thinker
- R Quick learner and adaptable
- Self-motivated and enthusiastic
- A Time management
- Yalue team work but can work independently
- A Focus on customer service
- R Technical analysis

## Interests and hobbies

- Team sports
- Streaming video games
- Family orientated
- Photography

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

#### Focus skills.

- ADVANCED C# and .NET
- Web services and forms
- 🔯 Full SQL and database design
- Basic front end languages: HTML, CSS
- Basic python
- Systems engineering and design
- Processing and logic concepts
- Program design and documentation
- Hardware and security

#### Network skills.

- Working knowledge in service provider industries
- Switching (Inter-VLAN Routing, STP, RSTP, MSTP, VLAN, VTP)
- Routing Protocols: RIP, EIGRP, OSPF
- Implementing traffic filters using access-list, prefix-list and distribute-list.
- Implementing NAT, PAT.
- Knowledge of TCP/IP Model, OSI Layers.
- Implementing switching with redundancy
- Comprehensive understanding of networking concepts pertaining to LAN, WAN
- Working Experience on Cisco devices
- Good understanding of cabling of Rack and patch panel
- Hands-on experience on Routers like Cisco (1800, 2600, 2800, 3745, 7200, 1000, 4000 series) and Switches like Cisco (2900, 35XX, 36XX, 4500, 6500series)
- Microsoft Office

## **ADDITIONAL**

- △ Eager and willing to learn new technologies and open to training
- Can travel or work from home
- Letter of higher certificate completion available
- A References and transcripts available on request